When I was a kid, I was obsessed with the Guinness Book of World Records,
في صغري، كنت مولعة بموسوعة (جينيس) للأرقام القياسية العالمية
and I really wanted to set a world record myself.
رغبت في تسجيل رقم قياسي بنفسي.
But there was just one small problem:
لكن واجهتني مشكلة صغيرة:
I had absolutely no talent.
لم أكن أمتلك أي موهبة.
So I decided to set a world record in something
لذا قررت أن أسجل رقمًا قياسيًا
that demanded absolutely no skill at all.
في أمر لا يتطلب أي موهبة على الإطلاق.
I decided to set a world record
قررت أن أسجل رقمًا قياسيًا
in crawling.
في الحَبْو.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, the record at the time was 12 and a half miles,
كان الرقم حينها 12 ميل ونصف،
and for some reason, this seemed totally manageable.
ولسبب ما، بدا ذلك سهل المنال للغاية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I recruited my friend Anne,
وظّفتُ صديقتي (آن)،
and together we decided, we didn't even need to train.
وقررنا معًا أننا لا نحتاج حتى للتدريب.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And on the day of our record attempt,
وفي يوم محاولة تحطيم الرقم القياسي،
we put furniture pads on the outside of our good luck jeans
وضعنا أغطية الأثاث القطنية على بنطالينا جالبيْ الحظ
and we set off,
وبدأنا الحبو،
and right away, we were in trouble,
وفي الحال وقعنا في ورطة،
because the denim was against our skin
لأن القماش الخشن التصق بالجلد مباشرةً
and it began to chafe,
وبدأ القماش يهترئ،
and soon our knees were being chewed up.
وسرعان ما تضررت ركبتانا.
Hours in,
وبعد ساعات،
it began to rain.
بدأت تمطر،
Then, Anne dropped out.
بعد ذلك، انسحبت (آن).
Then, it got dark.
ثم حل الظلام.
Now, by now, my knees were bleeding through my jeans,
كانت ركبتاي حينها تنزفان عبر بنطالي،
and I was hallucinating from the cold
وكنت أهذي من البرد
and the pain and the monotony.
والألم والملل.
And to give you an idea of the suffer-fest that I was undergoing,
ولأعطيكم فكرة عن حجم المعاناة التي مررت بها،
the first lap around the high school track took 10 minutes.
استغرقت اللفة الأولى حول مسار المدرسة 10 دقائق.
The last lap took almost 30.
أما الأخيرة فحوالي 30 دقيقة.
After 12 hours of crawling,
بعد 12 ساعة من الحبو،
I stopped,
توقفت،
and I had gone eight and a half miles.
وكنت قد قطعت 8 أميال ونصف.
So I was short of the 12-and-a-half-mile record.
كنت قريبة من تحطيم رقم الـ12 ميل ونصف.
Now, for many years, I thought this was a story of abject failure,
الآن، بعد مرور هذه السنوات كنت أظن بأنها قصة فشل ذريع،
but today I see it differently,
لكن اليوم أرى الأمر بنظرة مختلفة،
because when I was attempting the world record,
لأن أثناء محاولتي لتحطيم الرقم القياسي،
I was doing three things.
كنت أقوم بثلاثة أمور.
I was getting outside my comfort zone,
كنت أخرج من منطقة راحتي.
I was calling upon my resilience,
كنت أختبر قوة التحمل لدي.
and I was finding confidence in myself
كنت أبحث عن الثقة في نفسي
and my own decisions.
وفي قراراتي الخاصة.
I didn't know it then,
لم أدرك ذلك حينها،
but those are not the attributes of failure.
لكن هذه لم تكن سمات الفشل.
Those are the attributes of bravery.
بل هي سمات الشجاعة.
Now, in 1989, at the age of 26,
في عام 1989 عندما بلغت عامي الـ26،
I became a San Francisco firefighter,
أصبحت إطفائية في (سان فرانسيسكو)،
and I was the 15th woman in a department of 1,500 men.
كنت المرأة رقم 15 في قسم يتألف من 1500 رجل.
And as you can imagine, when I arrived
وكما تتخيلون، عندما وصلت
there were many doubts about whether we could do the job.
كان يتم التشكيك بقدرتنا على أداء العمل.
So even though I was a 5'10", 150-pound collegiate rower,
برغم أني كنت مجدّفة جامعية بطول 177 سم ووزن 68 كجم،
and someone who could endure 12 hours of searing knee pain --
وأتحمل 12 ساعة من ألم الركبة الحارق،
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I knew I still had to prove my strength and fitness.
عرفت أنني مضطرة لإثبات قوتي ولياقتي.
So one day a call came in for a fire,
وفي يوم ما وردنا اتصال بنشوب حريق،
and sure enough, when my engine group pulled up,
وتأكدت تمامًا عندما رأيت الفريق المحرك يستعد،
there was black smoke billowing from a building off an alleyway.
كان يوجد دخان أسود ينبعث من مبنى في أحد الأزقة.
And I was with a big guy named Skip,
وكنت مع رجل ضخم يدعى (سكيب).
and he was on the nozzle, and I was right behind,
وكان يمسك فوهة الخرطوم بينما كنت خلفه مباشرةً،
and it was a typical sort of fire.
كان ذلك مثالًا نموذجيًا للحريق.
It was smoky, it was hot,
كان الدخان كثيفًا وساخنًا،
and all of a sudden,
وبشكل مفاجئ،
there was an explosion,
حدث انفجار،
and Skip and I were blown backwards,
مما دفعني أنا و(سكيب) للخلف،
my mask was knocked sideways,
سقط قناعي جانبًا،
and there was this moment of confusion.
كانت لحظة مليئة بالارتباك.
And then I picked myself up,
وبعدها استجمعت قواي،
I groped for the nozzle,
تحسست بيداي باحثةً عن الخرطوم،
and I did what a firefighter was supposed to do:
وفعلت ما يفترض أن يفعله أي إطفائي:
I lunged forward,
اندفعتُ للأمام،
opened up the water
وفتحت المياه
and I tackled the fire myself.
وتصديت للحريق بنفسي.
The explosion had been caused by a water heater,
حدث الانفجار بسبب سخان المياه،
so nobody was hurt, and ultimately it was not a big deal,
لم يتأذ أحد وفي النهاية لم يكن الأمر خطيرًا،
but later Skip came up to me and said,
جاءني (سكيب) لاحقًا وقال:
"Nice job, Caroline,"
"أحسنت صنعًا يا (كارولاين)،"
in this surprised sort of voice.
بنبرة صوت توحي بالاندهاش.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I was confused, because the fire hadn't been difficult physically,
شعرت بالحيرة لأن الحريق لم يكن شديدًا لهذه الدرجة،
so why was he looking at me with something like astonishment?
إذن لماذا كان ينظر إلي بهذه الدهشة؟
And then it became clear:
واتضح لي الأمر بعد ذلك،
Skip, who was by the way a really nice guy
(سكيب) الذي كان بالمناسبة رجلًا لطيفًا للغاية
and an excellent firefighter,
وإطفائيًا بارعًا،
not only thought that women could not be strong,
لم يكن يعتقد فقط أن المرأة لا تستطيع أن تكون قوية،
he thought that they could not be brave either.
بل أيضًا لا تستطيع أن تتحلى بالشجاعة.
And he wasn't the only one.
ولم يكن الوحيد الذي يعتقد ذلك.
Friends, acquaintances and strangers,
الأصدقاء والمعارف والغرباء،
men and women throughout my career
الرجال والنساء على مدار مهنتي
ask me over and over,
سألوني مرارًا وتكرارًا،
"Caroline, all that fire, all that danger,
"(كارولاين)، كل هذه النيران وكل هذا الخطر،
aren't you scared?"
ألا تشعرين بالخوف؟"
Honestly, I never heard a male firefighter asked this.
بصراحة، لم أسمع أحد يسأل رجلًا إطفائيًا عن ذلك.
And I became curious.
حينها أصابني الفضول.
Why wasn't bravery expected of women?
لماذا لم تكن الشجاعة متوقعة من النساء؟
Now, the answer began to come
الآن بدأت الإجابة تتضح
when a friend of mine lamented to me
عندما جاء صديق لي يشتكي
that her young daughter was a big scaredy-cat,
أن ابنته الصغيرة كانت تخاف بشدة،
and so I began to notice,
ومن هنا بدأت ألاحظ،
and yes, the daughter was anxious,
أجل، الإبنة كانت قلقة،
but more than that, the parents were anxious.
لكن إضافةً لهذا، كان الآباء أيضًا كذلك.
Most of what they said to her when she was outside began with,
معظم الكلام الذي يقولونه لها عندما كانت تخرج من البيت،
"Be careful," "Watch out," or "No."
"احذري أو انتبهي أو لا تخرجي."
Now, my friends were not bad parents.
لم يكن أصدقائي آباء سيئين.
They were just doing what most parents do,
لكنهم كانوا يتعاملون مثل معظم الآباء،
which is cautioning their daughters much more than they caution their sons.
ألا وهو تنبيه بناتهم أكثر من أبنائهم.
There was a study involving a playground fire pole, ironically,
اُجريت دراسة تتضمن عمود تسلق في ساحة لعب، بشكل ساخر.
in which researchers saw that little girls were very likely to be warned
رأى فيها الباحثون أن الفتيات الصغيرات أكثر عرضة للتحذير
by both their moms and dads about the fire pole's risk,
بواسطة آبائهن وأمهاتهن من خطورة تسلقه،
and if the little girls still wanted to play on the fire pole,
وإذا أصرّت الفتيات على اللعب بعمود التسلق،
a parent was very likely to assist her.
من المرجح جدًا أن يساعدها أحد الوالدين.
But the little boys?
لكن الأولاد الصغار؟
They were encouraged to play on the fire pole
كانوا يتلقون التشجيع للعب بعمود التسلق
despite any trepidations that they might have,
برغم الذعر الذي قد ينتابهم،
and often the parents offered guidance on how to use it on their own.
وعادةً يقوم الآباء بإرشادهم إلى كيفية تسلقه بأنفسهم.
So what message does this send to both boys and girls?
إذن ما هي الرسالة الموجهة إلى كل من الأولاد والفتيات؟
Well, that girls are fragile and more in need of help,
حسنًا، الرسالة هي أن الفتيات ضعيفات ويحتجن دائمًا للمساعدة.
and that boys can and should master difficult tasks by themselves.
والأولاد قادرون على تولي المهام الصعبة بأنفسهم بل ويجب عليهم ذلك.
It says that girls should be fearful
وأن الفتيات يجب عليهن الشعور بالخوف
and boys should be gutsy.
والأولاد يجب أن يكونوا شجعان.
Now, the irony is that at this young age,
حسنًا، المفارقة في هذه السن المبكرة،
girls and boys are actually very alike physically.
أن البنات والأولاد في الواقع متشابهين بدنيًا.
In fact, girls are often stronger until puberty,
في الحقيقة، الفتيات هنّ أكثر قوة حتى سن البلوغ،
and more mature.
وأكثر نضجًا.
And yet we adults act
وحتى الآن نتصرف نحن البالغين
as if girls are more fragile
كما لو أن الفتيات أكثر ضعفًا
and more in need of help,
وفي حاجة لمزيد من المساعدة،
and they can't handle as much.
ولا يستطعن الاعتماد على أنفسهن كثيرًا.
This is the message that we absorb as kids,
هذه هي الرسالة التي نستوعبها في صغرنا،
and this is the message that fully permeates as we grow up.
وهذه هي الرسالة التي تتغلغل فينا بينما نكبر.
We women believe it, men believe it,
النساء يعتقدن هذا مثل الرجال،
and guess what?
واحزروا ماذا؟
As we become parents, we pass it on to our children,
وعندما نصبح آباء، ننقل هذا الشعور لأطفالنا،
and so it goes.
وهكذا يستمر الأمر.
Well, so now I had my answer.
حسنًا، حصلت على إجابتي الآن.
This is why women, even firewomen,
هذا هو سبب أن النساء حتى الإطفائيات منهن،
were expected to be scared.
من المتوقع أن يكنّ خائفات.
This is why women often are scared.
هذا هو السبب عادةً في شعور النساء بالخوف.
Now, I know some of you won't believe me when I tell you this,
الآن، أعلم أن بعضكم لن يصدقني عندما أقول هذا،
but I am not against fear.
لكني لست ضد الشعور بالخوف.
I know it's an important emotion, and it's there to keep us safe.
أعلم أنه إحساس مهم، ويعطينا الأمان.
But the problem is when fear is the primary reaction
لكن المشكلة هي عندما يكون الخوف هو رد الفعل الرئيسي
that we teach and encourage in girls
الذي نعلمه للفتيات ونشجعهن عليه
whenever they face something outside their comfort zone.
في كل مرة يواجهن أمرًا خارج نطاق منطقة الراحة.
So I was a paraglider pilot for many years --
كنت أحلق بمظلة (باراجليدر) لعدة سنوات،
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
and a paraglider is a parachute-like wing,
وهي مثل جناح مشابه للباراشوت،
and it does fly very well,
وتحلق بشكل جيد للغاية،
but to many people I realize it looks just like a bedsheet
لكن بالنسبة للعديد من الناس أدركت أنها تبدو مثل غطاء السرير
with strings attached.
وبها خيوط كثيرة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I spent a lot of time on mountaintops
وقضيت الكثير من الوقت فوق قمم الجبال
inflating this bedsheet,
أنفخ غطاء السرير هذا،
running off and flying.
أنطلق وأحلق.
And I know what you're thinking.
وأعلم فيما تفكرون.
You're like, Caroline, a little fear would make sense here.
تقولون لي أن الشعور ببعض الخوف هنا أمر منطقي.
And you're right, it does.
وأنتم على صواب فيما تفكرون.
I assure you, I did feel fear.
أؤكد لكم أنني شعرت بالخوف.
But on that mountaintop,
لكن فوق قمة الجبل،
waiting for the wind to come in just right,
انتظار هبوب الرياح في الوقت المناسب،
I felt so many other things, too:
شعرت بأشياء أخرى أيضًا:
exhilaration, confidence.
البهجة والثقة.
I knew I was a good pilot.
كنت أعرف أنني طيارة ماهرة.
I knew the conditions were good, or I wouldn't be there.
كنت أعلم أن الظروف مهيأة وإلا لما كنت هناك.
I knew how great it was going to be a thousand feet in the air.
عرفت مدى روعة أن تكون على ارتفاع ألف قدم في الهواء.
So yes, fear was there,
لذا أجل كنت أشعر بالخوف،
but I would take a good hard look at it,
لكني كنت أتمعن بشدة في الأمر،
assess just how relevant it was
وأقيّم حجم الخوف ومدى صلته
and then put it where it belonged,
وأضعه في مكانه،
which was more often than not
وكان الأمر عادةً مقاربًا
behind my exhilaration, my anticipation
للشعور بالبهجة والترقب
and my confidence.
وشعوري بالثقة.
So I'm not against fear.
لذا لست ضد الشعور بالخوف.
I'm just pro-bravery.
أنا فقط مؤيدة للتحلي بالشجاعة.
Now, I'm not saying your girls must be firefighters
لا أقول أن فتياتكم عليهن أن يصبحن إطفائيات
or that they should be paragliders,
أو أنه عليهن أن يحلقن بمظلة (باراجليدر)،
but I am saying that we are raising our girls to be timid, even helpless,
لكني أقول أننا نربي فتياتنا على الخوف وحتى العجز،
and it begins when we caution them against physical risk.
ويبدأ الأمر عندما نحذرهن ضد الخطر البدني.
The fear we learn and the experiences we don't
نعلمهن الخوف ولا نعطيهن الخبرة
stay with us as we become women
يظل الخوف معنا حتى نصبح راشدات
and morphs into all those things that we face and try to shed:
ونغير كل هذه الأمور التي نواجهها ونلقي الضوء عليها:
our hesitation in speaking out,
التردد في التحدث بصراحة،
our deference so that we can be liked
اختلافنا لأجل أن يحبنا الآخرون
and our lack of confidence in our own decisions.
وانعدام الثقة بقراراتنا الخاصة.
So how do we become brave?
إذن كيف نتحلى بالشجاعة؟
Well, here's the good news.
حسنًا، إليكم الأخبار الجيدة.
Bravery is learned,
الشجاعة صفة مكتسبة،
and like anything learned,
ومثلها مثل أي شيء نتعلمه،
it just needs to be practiced.
لكنها تتطلب الممارسة.
So first,
لذا أولًا:
we have to take a deep breath
علينا أن نأخذ نفسًا عميقًا
and encourage our girls
ونشجع فتياتنا
to skateboard, climb trees
على استخدام لوح التزلج وتسلق الأشجار
and clamber around on that playground fire pole.
والصعود على عمود التسلق في ساحة اللعب.
This is what my own mother did.
هذا ما فعلته أمي.
She didn't know it then,
لم تكن تعلم ذلك حينها،
but researchers have a name for this.
لكن لدى الباحثون اسم لهذا.
They call it risky play,
يسمونه اللعب المجازف،
and studies show that risky play is really important for kids, all kids,
وتظهر الدراسات أن اللعب بمجازفة مهم لجميع الأطفال
because it teaches hazard assessment,
لأنه يعلّم مهارة تقييم المخاطر،
it teaches delayed gratification,
وتأجيل الشعور بالإرضاء،
it teaches resilience,
ويعلّم القدرة على الصمود،
it teaches confidence.
ويعلم الثقة.
In other words,
بمعنى آخر،
when kids get outside and practice bravery,
عندما يكون الأطفال بالخارج ويمارسون الشجاعة،
they learn valuable life lessons.
فهم يتعلمون الدروس القيمة من الحياة.
Second, we have to stop cautioning our girls willy-nilly.
ثانيًا: علينا أن نتوقف عن تحذير الفتيات تلقائيًا.
So notice next time you say,
لاحظوا في المرة القادمة عندما تقولون:
"Watch out, you're going to get hurt,"
"انتبهي، ستجرحين نفسك،"
or, "Don't do that, it's dangerous."
أو "لاتفعلي ذلك إنه خطير."
And remember that often what you're really telling her
وتذكروا عادةً أن ما تقولونه لها فعلًا
is that she shouldn't be pushing herself,
أنه لا يجب عليها أن تجهد نفسها،
that she's really not good enough,
وأنها ليست جيدة بما فيه الكفاية،
that she should be afraid.
وأنها عليها أن تشعر بالخوف.
Third,
ثالثًا:
we women have to start practicing bravery, too.
نحن بصفتنا نساء علينا أن نبدأ في ممارسة الشجاعة أيضًا.
We cannot teach our girls until we teach ourselves.
لا يمكننا أن نعلّم فتياتنا قبل أن نعلّم أنفسنا.
So here's another thing:
لذا إليكم شيئًا آخر:
fear and exhilaration
الخوف والبهجة
feel very similar --
يتشابهان كثيرًا،
the shaky hands, the heightened heart rate,
الأيدي المرتعشة ومعدل ضربات القلب المرتفعة،
the nervous tension,
وتوتر الأعصاب،
and I'm betting that for many of you
وأستطيع التأكيد بأن العديد منكم
the last time you thought you were scared out of your wits,
في آخر مرة اعتقدتم فيها أنكم خائفون بشدة،
you may have been feeling mostly exhilaration,
قد يكون راودكم الشعور بالبهجة في الأغلب،
and now you've missed an opportunity.
والآن قد فاتتكم الفرصة.
So practice.
لذا عليكم بالممارسة.
And while girls should be getting outside to learn to be gutsy,
وبينما يجب على الفتيات أن يخرجن لتعلم الشجاعة،
I get that adults don't want to get on hoverboards or climb trees,
أتفهم بأن الكبار لا يريدون التزحلق أو تسلق الأشجار،
so we all should be practicing
لذا علينا جميعًا أن نمارس الشجاعة
at home, in the office
في البيت أو في العمل
and even right here getting up the guts
وحتى هنا استجمعوا شجاعتكم
to talk to someone that you really admire.
للتحدث مع من تحبون بشدة.
Finally, when your girl is, let's say,
في النهاية، لنقل أنه عندما تكون فتاتكم
on her bike on the top of the steep hill
على الدراجة فوق قمة تل شديد الانحدار
that she insists she's too scared to go down,
وأنها خائفة للغاية من النزول لأسفل،
guide her to access her bravery.
أرشدوها للتحلي بشجاعتها.
Ultimately, maybe that hill really is too steep,
في النهاية قد يكون هذا التل منحدرًا بشدة،
but she'll come to that conclusion through courage, not fear.
لكنها ستصل لهذه النتيجة عن طريق الشجاعة وليس الخوف.
Because this is not about the steep hill in front of her.
لأن هذا لا يتعلق بالتل المنحدر أمامها،
This is about the life ahead of her
بل يتعلق بالحياة أمامها
and that she has the tools
وأنها لديها القدرة
to handle and assess
لتولي زمام الأمور
all the dangers that we cannot protect her from,
وتقييم كافة المخاطر التي لا نستطيع حمايتها منها،
all the challenges that we won't be there to guide her through,
والتحديات التي لن نتواجد فيها لمساعدتها في تخطيها،
everything that our girls here
وكل شيء ستواجهه فتياتنا هنا
and around the world
وحول العالم
face in their future.
في مستقبلهن.
So by the way,
لذا بالمناسبة،
the world record for crawling today --
الرقم القياسي المسجَّل في الحبو اليوم،
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
is 35.18 miles,
هو 35.18 ميل،
and I would really love to see a girl go break that.
وأود بشدة أن أرى فتاة تحطم هذا الرقم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)